Guide to the Edward Stevens Sanborn Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Edward Stevens Sanborn Papers
1894-1936
RG 98
Yale University Divinity School Library
3.5
(7 boxes)
Sermons and biographical material document the life and work of a New England Congregational minister during the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Edward Stevens Sanborn (1866-1945) was a Yale Divinity School graduate who served various Congregational parishes in Connecticut, Massachusetts, and New Hampshire.
Sanborn, Edward Stevens, 1866-1945
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Leonard F. Sanborn.
Biographical / Historical
1866 Apr 19 Born in Kingston, New Hampshire
1892 B.A., Yale
1895 B.D. Yale Divinity School
1896-1899 Congregational minister in Ridgebury, CT, followed by pastorates in the following towns:
1900-1903 Georgetown, CT
1903-1907 East Hartland, CT
1907-1911 East Barrington, NH
1911-1915 Dover, MA
1915-1919 Gilmanton, NH
1919-1924 Canterbury, NH
1924-1931 Acworth, NH
1945 Died
Scope and Contents
This record group provides a detailed record of the work of a New England Congregational minister between the years 1896 and 1931.
The first series, Biographical Documentation, includes Yale and YDS class reports as well as material supplied by ESS's son, Leonard F. Sanborn, and a chronological record of activities for parishes served by ESS from 1896 to 1907. Similar records for ESS's pastorates in East Barrington, NH and Dover, MA have been given to the Congregational churches in those towns.
Series II, Sermons, consists of approximately 250 packets of manuscript sermon notes in numbered sequence, with supporting enclosures, primarily clippings from periodicals. Each sermon was preached several times, and the dates and places preached are noted on the sermon or its envelope. The dates listed in this finding aid are the earliest date preached for the first sermon in each box.
Arrangement
I. Biographical Documentation, 1896-1936
II. Sermons, 1894-1931
Congregationalists -- New Hampshire; Congregationalists -- Connecticut; Congregationalists -- Massachusetts; Clergy; Sanborn, Edward Stevens, 1866-1845
- Biographical Documentation, 1896-1936; Series I
  - Yale Class of 1892 Quindecennial Record, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - YDS Class of 1895 reports, 1905-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical sketch of ESS (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Parish records, 1896-1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sermons, 1894-1931; Series II
  - Nos. 2 -25, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Nos. 26 - 62, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 6-10)
  - Nos. 63 - 100, 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 11-16)
  - Nos. 101 - 138, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 17-21)
  - Nos. 139 - 172, 1899-1905 (Box 5, Folder 23-28)
  - Nos. 173 - 203, 1906-1923 (Box 6, Folder 29-34)
  - Nos. 204 - 250, unnumbered, 1924-1931 (Box 7, Folder 35)